This video will give you a quick
overview of working with journals in
Business Central. You can use journals
to perform most of your bookkeeping
tasks. In the business manager role
center, journals are found under
finance. The general journals are
general purpose journals used for almost
all bookkeeping tasks. But there are
also specific purpose journals. If
you're using the accountant ro center,
you will also find access to journals.
You will find the same set placed under
journals, including general
journals. The different journals work
almost the same way independent of
feature area. So, we'll focus on general
journals here. All journal types have
templates. Templates allow you to set up
parameters that control the different
journal
types. For a given journal type, you can
set up multiple journals to split up the
task either by type or between users
performing different bookkeeping tasks.
There are two basic ways of filling in a
journal with or without balancing
accounts. If you're new to Dynamics 365
or doing tasks like registering
reimbursements, it might be easier to
fill in journals line by line without
balancing accounts. For each line, you
specify the expense. You select the
account number and type in what the
expense is. This will give you a nice
overview of what you're doing and the
entries you work with. When you become
more familiar with journal posting, you
might find it easier to work with
balancing accounts per line. For each
expense, like a purchase invoice, you
type in the expense detail, such as tax
info, the amount, and then balance out
the journal line by line, specifying the
balancing account. This way reduces the
number of lines you must fill in, making
journal entry faster. You can always
check before you post the journal by
using the general journal test action.
It will generate a test report which you
can look
over. When you're satisfied with your
journal entries, you can post them. If
you make a mistake, you can always
reverse journal
entries. Find the entry usually by
searching the GL registers. Then use the
reverse register action. This will
reverse the entries completely and you
can post a new correct journal.
You now have an overview of general
journals in Business Central and know
how and where to find them. You can
always leave and come back to a journal.
No need to save your work. Thank you for
watching and good luck with your
bookkeeping in Business Central.